<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>a lit journal.</description>
    <link>http://alienmouth.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alienmouth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 18:04:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 18:04:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tables Without Chairs: A Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tables Without Chairs&quot; src=&quot;http://alienmouth.com/reviews/tables.png&quot; style=&quot;width:350px;height:350px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released late last year from House of Vlad, &amp;ldquo;Tables Without Chairs #1&amp;rdquo; throws its readers face-first into an carnival experience courtesy of Bud Smith and Brian Alan Ellis. Combining recurring characters and shout-outs with uncanny art by Waylon Thornton, this book intersperses quips and self-reflection to paint its wild collage. From the get-go, readers find the duo exchanging cover band ideas before moving to hilarious blurbs such as: &amp;ldquo;Brian Alan Ellis is like a scratch-off lottery ticket that you get for Christmas and HOLY SHIT I JUST WON $250 but your aunt who you owe $400 to is sitting right there so you hand it over and now it&amp;rsquo;s fresh in her mind that you still owe $150 FUCK! But he writes really good stories&amp;rdquo; (7). Besides clearly having a blast with the whole project, these writers manage to blend their respective styles of humor without ever losing speed, resulting in a lighthearted mood of leaking hot tubs and hellacious half-friends that continues to surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dark turntable celebration in the face of desertion, Brian Alan Ellis&amp;rsquo;s first half, &amp;ldquo;Sexy Time in the Spook House, Oh Yeah!&amp;rdquo; kick-starts the show with a werewolf of a fellow on the rebound. Both resisting and seeking sexy times &amp;ldquo;for this nightmare to scare us both awake&amp;rdquo; (27), Ellis&amp;rsquo;s main character hangs himself on the words of others, remembering his lost lover. Yet from this chaotic violence where &amp;ldquo;Nobody is good to one another. Nobody is good to anyone&amp;rdquo; (35), Ellis shifts gears entirely in his second section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ha-Ha! Sad Laughter&amp;rdquo; unfolds as an anti-literary litany, unloading non-stop cynicism and what-ifs to take on postal submissions, Goodreads trolling, and the #amwriting hashtag, among others. Rather than simply attacking the literary establishment with an outsider&amp;rsquo;s shallow contempt, Ellis confronts the scene&amp;rsquo;s sacred cows with an insider&amp;rsquo;s irony. Across thirty pages of fragments, we find suggestions for poetry readings at EDM raves, rejected submissions for a 25-words-only short story contest, 4 pages of pre-written blurbs, and other gems for making it big: &amp;ldquo;When at AWP, a productive thing to do is to frantically ask random people if they know what time Smash Mouth goes on&amp;rdquo; (70). Striking the right balance between self-deprecation and smugness, Brian Alan Ellis makes us laugh with one-liners like &amp;ldquo;Pop-Tart prize &amp;gt; Pushcart Prize&amp;rdquo; (58), while also bringing in relatable gloom from the writer&amp;rsquo;s life, trading your first novel for Burger King Groupons or hearing, &amp;ldquo;Good news: Your book just went into its third printing&amp;mdash;meaning that it is print-on-demand and only three people have purchased it&amp;rdquo; (70).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Ellis&amp;rsquo;s dark adventures and proposals for an &amp;ldquo;MFA in creative hiding&amp;rdquo; (80), Bud Smith brings readers into &amp;ldquo;Calm Face,&amp;rdquo; ten stories of everyday moments imbued with a kind of smooth wonder. Sometimes you forget your badge for work during a hectic morning commute, but everything falls into place so you don&amp;rsquo;t miss 30 minutes of pay (and you manage to steal a 5 gallon jug of gas to boot)! Whether laughing with his wife on mushrooms during freezing late night walks, or watching somebody almost get run over because there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;NO SUCH THING AS HOLDING SPOTS&amp;rdquo; (96) in the world of big-city parking, Smith&amp;rsquo;s characters wander through so many quick, random moments, making us laugh at their oddness. In fact, true to Smith&amp;rsquo;s title, these characters somehow manage to keep calm in the face of an anxious world, just as the Zen-like main character from &amp;ldquo;Apartment 13,&amp;rdquo; talking about his neighbor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_poem&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;He goes on and on and yells, &amp;ldquo;FUCKING BULLSHIT! MOTHER FUCKING SCUM SUCKING BULLSHIT!!!!&amp;rdquo; It comes and goes for hours. I sometimes wonder what he screams about but figure it&amp;rsquo;s probably just a video game. If it was anything else besides a video game, everyone in this apartment building would be dead. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the neighbor in the hall but have never mentioned the screaming, because, yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s none of my business, he&amp;rsquo;s home when he does it, he can scream. If it bothered me, I&amp;rsquo;d mention that. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. I imagine he&amp;rsquo;s playing Battletoads and is at the lava Jet Ski board. Only thing it can be.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(110-11)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout his stories, Smith shows we can let everything build up until it gets scary, or we can strip down and submerge into your apartment-flooding hot tub when people start pounding on your door!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world of mental health days, 50 mousetraps in need of opening, and writer residencies where &amp;ldquo;you stay where you are but you stop paying rent. The residency ends when your landlord calls the police&amp;rdquo; (46), Brian Alan Ellis and Bud Smith are on a mission to kick ass and gather laughs, or die trying. These wild novellas serve up truths of heartbreak and drudgery with laidback charm&amp;mdash;like a collision within a floor-shifting fun house, &amp;ldquo;Tables Without Chairs #1&amp;rdquo; keeps us smiling as it combines our monsters with the daily 9-to-5 grind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;Tables Without Chairs #1&amp;rdquo; from House of Vlad as both Paperback and E-book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Tables-Without-Chairs-Brian-Ellis/dp/0692480145/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1443647465&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=tables%20without%20chairs&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Brian Alan Ellis can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianalanellis&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianalanellis.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, and has a book of humorous non-fiction coming out in March from House of Vlad called &amp;ldquo;A Series of Pained Facial Expressions Made While Shredding Air Guitar&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bud Smith can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://budsmithwrites.com/&quot;&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Bud_Smith&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and has a novel coming out in April from Artistically Declined Press called &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m From Electric Peak&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Brian and Bud&amp;nbsp;are currently reading subs for &amp;ldquo;Tables Without Chairs #2&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; an anthology of Bad Jobs. Send your suffering to &lt;a href=&quot;http://houseofvlad.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;House of Vlad!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Review by &lt;a href=&quot;http://andlohespoke.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Christopher Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 11:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2016/02/15/tables/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2016/02/15/tables/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salt is for Curing: A Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;salt is for curing&quot; class=&quot;inline_image&quot; src=&quot;http://alienmouth.com/reviews/salt.png&quot; style=&quot;width:350px;height:350px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freshly served by Sator Press, Sonya Vatomsky&amp;rsquo;s first full-length collection, &amp;ldquo;Salt is For Curing&amp;rdquo; uses its dark feasts and folklore to explore the frailty of our memories and bodies. With photography by Sator&amp;rsquo;s founding editor, the cover&amp;rsquo;s salt circle invokes and repels darkness, sealing the poems within. Guiding readers through its three courses, Vatomsky&amp;rsquo;s poetry is a truly generous offering, complete with aperitif and digestif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the title reminds how we can hold onto things for an almost unnatural length of time, much of this collection commemorates what&amp;rsquo;s passed. The opening poem, &amp;ldquo;Bathymetry,&amp;rdquo; stretches from old legends of empowerment and oppression all the way to the present, as we&amp;rsquo;re told: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got the kind of light / you name galaxies after. / Andromeda, for example, / which means &amp;ldquo;ruler of men&amp;rdquo; / so, of course / they stripped her naked and chained her / to a rock&amp;rdquo; (11). Like a dinner toast for a death, this collection&amp;rsquo;s recurring spells and other forms crystallize facts for future audiences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_poem&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;Apotheosis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The recipe called for murder; I did not misread it:&amp;nbsp;6 SPRIGS FRESH DILL, as much&amp;nbsp;SALT&amp;nbsp;as you can stand,&amp;nbsp;and take a&amp;nbsp;KNIFE&amp;nbsp;to the one that failed you.&amp;nbsp;1 WHOLE POTATO, 1 WHOLE CARROT. You will not be cold this winter, you will not.&amp;nbsp;Locate the&amp;nbsp;JOINT, move the&amp;nbsp;BONE&amp;nbsp;back and forth; it can be&amp;nbsp;hard to find the&amp;nbsp;ARTICULATION POINT&amp;nbsp;with the sobs still lodged&amp;nbsp;in your throat like fish bones. Chop the&amp;nbsp;DILL&amp;nbsp;into fine green shards;&amp;nbsp;they are the forest you bury him in. They are the fog&amp;nbsp;on the fallen leaves on the wet snow on the soil. They are the wood frog and the arctic lamprey and the brown bear&amp;nbsp;leaving trails in the opposite direction. Use your&amp;nbsp;KNIFE&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;TRIM excess&amp;nbsp;FAT,&amp;nbsp;REMOVE&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;BONE&amp;nbsp;with minimal damage&amp;nbsp;to the meat, turn his memory to the grounds that sit&amp;nbsp;at the bottom of your porcelain cup painted in wild strawberries: a fortune teller&amp;rsquo;s ephemera. Use the tip of your&amp;nbsp;KNIFE &amp;mdash; not the blade,&amp;nbsp;lest he leave rings on you like an aging tree &amp;mdash; in short&amp;nbsp;flicking motions.&amp;nbsp;REMOVE&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;BONE&amp;nbsp;with minimal damage&amp;nbsp;to the meat. As much&amp;nbsp;SALT&amp;nbsp;as you can stand, rubbed the way you&amp;rsquo;d rub&amp;nbsp;an ache until it gives in beneath you. Little peat bog, little бог,&amp;nbsp;little God. Ivan the Fool slept on an oven and so will you. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; (34)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether by broiling, carving, or extracting, these poems address grief on their own terms. Blending personal experience with instruction, Vatomsky teaches us that tears are a surprisingly fine substitute for most ingredients, and that, &amp;ldquo;To brew a love potion is to kill yourself but to poison is to breathe&amp;rdquo; (71). But these poems also serve as timelines, occupying the past to resist forgetting. With its many references to food and language, &amp;ldquo;Salt is For Curing&amp;rdquo; blurs the line between identity and context, and how we place ourselves within our own history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet these poems recognize that no amount of salt can preserve something forever. Food must be eaten, or it perishes. Bodies must be buried, or hidden. Leading us into the swamplands by a &amp;ldquo;chain of rope and scarves,&amp;rdquo; the speaker laments: &amp;ldquo;I am being carefully and / systemically forgotten&amp;rdquo; (22), as if even memories decay in the mire. But these poems know the dirty details required for moving on, whether from a stern mother&amp;rsquo;s advice, or somebody who&amp;rsquo;s learned the &amp;ldquo;safest place to bury a body / is in another body / is in your own body&amp;rdquo; (17). Vatomsky knows we learn through pain&amp;mdash;licking our wounds until the taste of blood no longer scares us&amp;mdash;as a witch &amp;ldquo;can only be burned so many times before she thinks hmm / something has got to change here&amp;rdquo; (73).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Salt is For Curing&amp;rdquo; offers the ultimate reward in exchange for your darkest red. Making a thick paste from a phoenix&amp;rsquo;s bones to reexamine resurrection myths, these poems count all 32 teeth, then eat your words with bread. Sonya Vatomsky reflects upon salt and suffering, creating a literary love potion that&amp;rsquo;s equal parts wishing well and butcher&amp;rsquo;s hook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;Salt is For Curing&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/l/saltisforcuring&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://sator.press/&quot;&gt;Sator&amp;nbsp;Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://maudlinhouse.tumblr.com/post/133352521890&quot;&gt;this great interview&lt;/a&gt; with Sonya at Maudlin House, which includes interesting facts about the book&amp;rsquo;s roots and exorcisms.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sonya Vatomsky can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/coolniceghost&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://sonyavatomsky.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sonya is currently working on poems exploring gender and mental illness&amp;ndash;you can read 3 in the next Noble / Gas Quarterly. They have also been guest-editing an issue of Anthropoid and will soon be joining the collective in some kind of permanent capacity.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; Review by &lt;a href=&quot;http://andlohespoke.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Christopher Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 11:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2016/01/15/salt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2016/01/15/salt/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Myth+Magic: A Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;meta + myth&quot; class=&quot;inline_image&quot; src=&quot;http://alienmouth.com/reviews/myth.png&quot; style=&quot;width:200px;height:200px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 by Nicci Mechler, Porkbelly Press is a queer-friendly, feminist press focused on producing limited and small edition, handbound chapbooks. Having already released a few pocket-sized anthologies (inspired by such themes as Emily Dickinson&amp;rsquo;s life + the art of letters), the press has recently released its fourth compilation, &amp;ldquo;Myth+Magic,&amp;rdquo; which features poetry and prose exploring &amp;ldquo;folk tale, fable, fairy tale, gods, monsters, myth, magic, tricksters, divination, witchcraft, and herbalism.&amp;rdquo; Adorned with gorgeous cover art, &amp;ldquo;under water,&amp;rdquo; by Angie Reed Garner, this collection charms our senses and expectations, providing a glimpse into a buried, fantastical warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the seven poets in this collection refuse simple retellings, such as in Andrea Blythe&amp;rsquo;s opening poem, &amp;ldquo;Red Riding Hood Remembers,&amp;rdquo; which reexamines the supposed facts of the classic tale&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;how she had / not once, not once, ever asked to be saved&amp;rdquo; (9). Likewise, M. Brett Gaffney&amp;rsquo;s fable quickly immerses readers in the life of a young hunter as she learns something unexpected of the real world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inline_poem&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hunters&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After supper she pulls on boots,&lt;br /&gt;
prepares her heart.&lt;br /&gt;
The girl is small but carries the gun&lt;br /&gt;
like she would a baby, twig fingers light&lt;br /&gt;
on its tongue of a trigger.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Her father hoists his rifle, heavy with ammo,&lt;br /&gt;
the glint of his knife like teeth in the fading light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They hunt at twilight, when wild things stumble&lt;br /&gt;
onto the roads like drowsy children,&lt;br /&gt;
thickets busy with thorns.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Up in the old oak they wait&lt;br /&gt;
for beasts that have no godly name.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She still remembers the sound&lt;br /&gt;
of the wolf&amp;rsquo;s howl&lt;br /&gt;
as her father&amp;rsquo;s bullet&lt;br /&gt;
found home in hot flesh.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How the animal&amp;rsquo;s hide&lt;br /&gt;
all fur and full of stars,&lt;br /&gt;
rippled like an angry ocean&lt;br /&gt;
until it sloughed off to something&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;smoother and human.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That night she saw a man&amp;rsquo;s body for the first time&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;mdash;the cut of thigh like cloudy bread,&lt;br /&gt;
soft gathering of hair below his belly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The way his eyes told her a story about herself,&lt;br /&gt;
one she tucked inside her jacket&lt;br /&gt;
along with his sharpest fang. (10-11).&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further instilling freshness into familiar tales, Laura Bylenok&amp;rsquo;s two poems, &amp;ldquo;Rape of Electra&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Caiman,&amp;rdquo; drive the reader through dark scenes of sacrifice, rebirth, and divided waters. Throughout these pieces we find the natural world, always sharp and present, as Suzanna Anderson shares a haiku about a wound-licking lilac, or Monica Rico ponders heartbeats and humidity, &amp;ldquo;the predictable / human body / easily missed&amp;rdquo; (17), suffocating flowers, and baby snapping turtles. But these poets are also our guides, as Lisa Megraw&amp;rsquo;s first poem reveals a witchy path to &amp;ldquo;a mythical / place hidden between worlds&amp;rdquo; (25) in &amp;ldquo;How to Take the Raven as Your Birth Sign,&amp;rdquo; with advice such as: &amp;ldquo;Peel the shadows off migrating birds / then under covers of darkness / slip inside their bruised / emptiness&amp;rdquo; (24). In further poems of instruction, Sarah Ann Winn&amp;rsquo;s whimsical &amp;ldquo;How to Fold a Dream&amp;rdquo; has the reader stack mockingbirds inside of themselves, packing away Venus and constellations to craft a stowaway dream you can examine from your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Succinct and controlled, the three prose pieces in &amp;ldquo;Myth+Magic&amp;rdquo; paint encounters between humans and the supernatural. &amp;ldquo;Hamadryad&amp;rdquo; by Lucas Olson details grim irony as a spirit of the woods finds her sister&amp;rsquo;s former tree-self returned as a weapon, wielded by a weeping man. Indeed, &amp;ldquo;there is never any life in an axe&amp;rdquo; (12), as tragedy can only end one way. And halfway through the anthology, Marlana Patton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Juliet&amp;rdquo; is a surprisingly moving tale where an enormous spider&amp;rsquo;s infatuation with a farmer offers the only possibility of her surviving the freezing winter: &amp;ldquo;Only a few days ago he caught a small jumping spider very near the shed. She saw delight in his face as he watched it spring from one hand to the other. He could understand this&amp;rdquo; (22-23). Closing the anthology is &amp;ldquo;The Lemon Seed&amp;rdquo; by Leah Browning, where a girl swallows a lemon seed daily, hoping for it to grow&amp;mdash;only to find her wish suddenly, rapidly fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Myth+Magic&amp;rdquo; shows us how beauty and danger can often occupy and captivate within the same space&amp;mdash;which makes what comes next all the more unreal. Rejecting the ordinary with every line, the writers in this anthology not only engage their readers with imaginative details, but also use these same concise worlds to introduce the everyday hardships of love, surprise, and sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;Myth+Magic&amp;rdquo; from Porkbelly Press&amp;rsquo;s bookstore &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/244868509/mythmagic-limited-edition-anthology&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (while supplies last). Or get it as part of the &amp;ldquo;Any 5 for 35&amp;rdquo; bundle deal, which I highly recommend (found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/217126321/any-5-for-35-porkbelly-press-sampler?ref=shop_home_feat_4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Stay tuned for &amp;ldquo;Sky+Sea,&amp;rdquo; an upcoming anthology Mechler says will showcase &amp;ldquo;work inspired by the stars, planets, moon, skies, and the depths of the sea&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;submissions begin in early 2016!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://porkbellypress.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Porkbelly Press&lt;/a&gt; can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/porkbellypress?fref=ts&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porkbellypress&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/shop/WickedLittleHeart&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Review by &lt;a href=&quot;http://andlohespoke.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Christopher Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 11:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/12/15/myth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/12/15/myth/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Animal Problems: A Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;animal problems&quot; class=&quot;inline_image&quot; src=&quot;http://alienmouth.com/reviews/katies.png&quot; style=&quot;width:350px;height:350px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flagship title from Electric Cereal&amp;rsquo;s recent press expansion, Katie Foster&amp;rsquo;s debut collection, &amp;ldquo;Animal Problems,&amp;rdquo; reconciles the rift between our human and animal selves, sharing the emotional hurdles in the process. Even the cover art, aptly crafted by Adriana Lafarga, embodies this unique blend of intimacy, instinct, and vulnerability. Equally at home in either allegory or reflection, these poems inhabit speculation and deeper emotions in the same landscape, as we&amp;rsquo;re told: &amp;ldquo;Here is / everything else I do not know for / sure: how a needle enters skin / (pushes it open, really, holds a human / space), &amp;amp; what is the capital of Nebraska / &amp;amp; where I will be when I stop / loving you&amp;rdquo; (31).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether looking at dueling ownerships in the title poem or the sliminess of heartbreak, &amp;ldquo;Animal Problems&amp;rdquo; showcases its clever mix of creatures for a wide range of moods. Sometimes the beasts claim you, before burying you beneath the soil. Other times you want the soggy dog to rescue you, but he can&amp;rsquo;t. Foster knows how our wants emerge and clash in seemingly convoluted ways, as in the succinct series named &amp;ldquo;Two Things I No Longer Have Come Together,&amp;rdquo; where the speaker&amp;rsquo;s ex-lover and &amp;ldquo;all / American boy dog&amp;rdquo; (13) simultaneously wander the same poetic ecosystem. Two sides of the speaker&amp;rsquo;s heart collide, just as her dog suddenly finds itself eye-to-eye with a towering black bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is how much of Foster&amp;rsquo;s collection succeeds, contrasting the animal qualities inside us against our societal fears. Along these lines, Foster&amp;rsquo;s poem, &amp;ldquo;Inventory,&amp;rdquo; is a testament to such dichotomies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inline_poem&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Inventory&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mom is living. Mom&amp;rsquo;s mom is dead.&lt;br /&gt;
My houseplants are living. Myspace is dead.&lt;br /&gt;
Punk is dead. The rich are living.&lt;br /&gt;
Arnold Schwartzenegger is living. Robots are dead.&lt;br /&gt;
The ends of my hair are dead. Yogurt is living.&lt;br /&gt;
The squirrel on route 9 is definitely dead. Debts are living.&lt;br /&gt;
What I forgot is dead. A walk is living.&lt;br /&gt;
Door home is dead. Getting a new wife is living.&lt;br /&gt;
The other car is dead. Strangers on the internet are living.&lt;br /&gt;
Having a lot of sex is living. Baby teeth are dead.&lt;br /&gt;
Period blood is dead. Too much spit is living.&lt;br /&gt;
Dry grass is dead. April is half living.&lt;br /&gt;
The cicadas are dead. You are living.&lt;br /&gt;
I am not dead. I am not dead.&lt;br /&gt;
You are not here. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; (18)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though even as the speaker organizes and accumulates details, only so much can be controlled in our lives. In the poem, &amp;ldquo;Image,&amp;rdquo; Foster further contrasts images against their antithesis&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;a child wearing all blue&amp;rdquo; is not &amp;ldquo;a soft brick,&amp;rdquo; just as a &amp;ldquo;lone seagull circling a Walmart&amp;rdquo; is not &amp;ldquo;your feelings&amp;rdquo; (19). Whether we&amp;rsquo;re shown a shapeshifting dog arising from chemicals, an orgy that never happens, or drunken playground antics with Viking symbols, we continually find the speaker reaching for long-gone connections as love enters and leaves our lives. But Foster is no fool, knowing one must learn to accept loss; after all, &amp;ldquo;The death is what lasts&amp;rdquo; (57). Otherwise you might find yourself falling into traps, watched by people who withhold the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Animal Problems&amp;rdquo; knows whether to need a knife or a key. It leads us into the woods to make a mess of our hair, exploring the dark places closed off in the aftermath. Like the villanelle&amp;rsquo;s refrain, &amp;ldquo;I drive the space between us&amp;rdquo; (32), Katie Foster finds a way to both embody and combat distance. Whether following the girl slug undone by love, or reflecting upon &amp;ldquo;How unusual it is // to disappear&amp;rdquo; (35), these poems pit our animal hearts against everything our culture does to disturb us, suggesting that maybe all our problems aren&amp;rsquo;t nearly as complicated as we might think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find &amp;ldquo;Animal Problems&amp;rdquo; from Electric Cereal&amp;rsquo;s bookstore &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.electriccereal.com/bookstore/animal-problems-katie-foster/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Katie Foster can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://00000katiefoster.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://newhive.com/kfster/profile/feed&quot;&gt;New Hive&lt;/a&gt;. She&amp;rsquo;s currently pulling together a portfolio for grad school apps, still writing new poems frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 11:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/11/15/animal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/11/15/animal/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>THERE WAS SO MUCH BEAUTIFUL LEFT: A Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;there is within humans a certain propensity for our emotional beings to atrophy over time. whatever the different circumstances, we have all known people who have allowed their capacities for love and empathy to deteriorate through small acts of neglect, violence, or pride&amp;mdash;the weariness that presses on the bones, attempting to warp them. Raul Alvarez&amp;rsquo;s THERE WAS SO MUCH BEAUTIFUL LEFT is about that tendency, or, perhaps, about that weariness; about succumbing and remaking, overcoming; about starting small and growing painfully but without fear; about coping and then learning to do better than that. this book is an ill, holy bonfire in the desert scratching messages to something like god or the space between two strangers standing at the same bus stop having really bad days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
here&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;from &amp;ldquo;RAPID CYCLING&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;lingering sexuality&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;which takes your mind and makes it&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;two, divided and divisive&amp;mdash;I know it like the sunshine&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;seeping through the window reflecting off my ring&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;finger touching my coffee&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;cup silently begging to be let in please come in!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;from one of the untitled poems about the devil in part 2:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;For five blurry years&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;we&amp;rsquo;ve owned the same ranch dressing&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;neither of us remember buying it&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;we don&amp;rsquo;t remember buying any of our condiments&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;from &amp;ldquo;IT&amp;rsquo;S IMPORTANT TO BE HAPPY ABOUT HOW SAD YOU ARE&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;I know I&amp;rsquo;ve said I love you too many times in this poem but it&amp;rsquo;s okay because it&amp;rsquo;s a rhetorical device. Rhetorical devices are language tricks you can use to tell people you love them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;What I&amp;rsquo;m saying is I owe a lot to people.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;What I&amp;rsquo;m saying is if there is anything worthwhile about growing up religious is that you will never stop believing in magic no matter what you tell yourself.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;from &amp;ldquo;NOTES ON JOY&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;quot;Fuck that. Take pain and loss like late season snow into your mouth&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
everyone wants to sign your cast so badly. people have come up with thousands of ways to add love to pain even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix anything. you gotta remember the point of all this living, its that people want to be bandages and not fists except sometimes people get really used to being fists and its hard/impossible/sacred to remind them that they&amp;rsquo;re not fists.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
sometimes things never had a chance to choose between bandage and fist and those things can become hospitals and healing is always on the heels of pain, which causes our hands to reach out and become entwined with the hands of those around us. perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the only human universal and its why we try so hard for everyone around us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
i think i learned these things from Raul&amp;rsquo;s book. or maybe i always knew them and this book just reminded me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can get a copy of &amp;quot;THERE WAS SO MUCH BEAUTIFUL LEFT&amp;quot; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boost-house.com/store/raul-alvarez&quot;&gt;boost house&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 12:06:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/10/15/there/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alienmouth.com/reviews/2015/10/15/there/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
